Su Shen

Software Engineer

Phone: (630) 991-8515 Email: <u>sshen2009@gmail.com</u>

Website: https://sushen2.github.io

Summary: Seeking a returnship opportunity to transfer my project skills to a software engineering role. With 12 years serving in the Architecture, Design, Construction, and Developing industry, a strong background in large-scale mixed-use developments including office, retail, hotel, entertainment, academic and high-end residential uses. My knowledge and experience working complex national and international projects makes her a strong asset to any project team.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGNER ARCHITECT — RTKL, Chicago, IL

Feb 2010 - May 2013

- Valued as a strong asset to the company on any project team with knowledge and
 experience working complex national and international projects; with a strong background
 in a variety of large-scale mixed-use developments including office, retail, hotel, and
 entertainment, academic and high-end residential uses
- Designed, Coordinate, and Accomplished over 15 projects: Kunming Rainbow Yunnan First City, Shanghai Qingpu Commercial district, Chengdu Chunxi Road Suning Plaza, Qingdao Laoshan Financial District Landmark, Guangzhou Zhangjiagang Twin Towers & Huadu Commercial District, Vile Parle high end residential development in Mumbai, India

ARCHITECTURAL ASSISTANT — Skidmore, Owings, & Merrill, Chicago, IL Nov 2006 - Dec 2008

- Directed and Established city scale and complex projects with highly efficient modeling system: Jumeirah Garden City master planning, Emirates Tower site master plan with expansions designs
- Coordinated and Communicated with international clients and consultant parties and experts among various projects
- Accomplished more than 13 global-wide constructed projects: Pearl River Tower, North Bund Plaza and Zhengzhou Greenland Plaza in China, Canary Wharf design in London, Dallas Tower and Denver Veteran hospital design and additional projects
- **Produced** and **assisted** auditing architectural packages through all designing phases, from competition, schematic, design development to construction documents

GRADUATE ASSISTANT — School of Architecture & Planning, SUNY Buffalo, Buffalo, NY Feb 2005 - Sep 2005

- Prepared documentation, conceptual designs and drawing for project presentation
- Communicated and with government representatives and experts
- Participated in 3 urban scale designs: Buffalo Greenways System, Buffalo Olmsted Parks Renovation, Buffalo Inner Harbor and Outer Harbor Plan
- Coordinated sketches on charette and create documentation

ASSISTANT ARCHITECT — Architecture Design and Research Institute, China State Construction Engineering, Beijing, China Aug 2002 - Aug 2004

- Led a 5 person group in designing for public and private projects
- **Prepared** presentation with physical models and renderings for construction biddings; **Negotiating** with clients and consultants
- Developed designs more than12 projects: Tianjin New Shopping Center, Dormitory
 Building for People's University of China, Cultural & Scientific Building for Shenzhen
 University, China in Egypt Consular building Renovation Design

MODELING, RENDERING, AND ANIMATION ARTIST — Crystal Digital Technology Company, Beijing, China Aug 2001 - Aug 2002

- Created more than 70 prospective presentations and 50 scenes in virtual animations by application of digital media for competition and advertising projects
- Participated and Accomplished over 18 projects: Propaganda Animation for Beijing's Olympic Game 2008, Beijing New Embassy Town, China National Film Museum

Software Mastery

- AutoCAD
- 3ds max
- Rhinoceros
- SketchUp
- Revit
- Maya
- Photoshop
- InDesign
- Illustrator
- Premiere
- MS Office

Programming Proficiency

HTML

Development Tools and IDEs

- GitHub
- Visual Studio Code
- IntelliJ
- PyCharm

<u>Programming</u> <u>Trainings</u>

- Javascript
- CSS
- Python
- Java
- Vue.js
- Spring Boot
- SQL

Spoken Languages

- Chinese
- English

EDUCATION

Master of Architecture — University of Buffalo, The State University of New York, Buffalo, Aug 2004 - Aug 2006

Bachelor of Architecture — *Tianjin University*, China Sep 1996 - Jul 2001